Speaker 1: It's Thursday, August 8th, 2024.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about fragrances.
Speaker 1: Feelings that go into your nose.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, on the way home today, I encountered a situation of environmental storytelling on the subway that had a surprising outcome.
Speaker 1: So, I get on the subway and it's really crowded and really hot and everyone's kind of surly because, you know, it's raining and it's been raining for like a week and a half now in the city.
Speaker 1: I'm on the 7 train and there's an area that's kind of open near the back of one of the 7 cars, so I think, well, there's probably a problem over there, but I only have to go a few stops, so I'm going to shove my way over there.
Speaker 1: I shove my way over there and I encounter what I first believed to be one kind of situation, but then by inspecting and regarding the scene before me for a few minutes, I was able to figure out what had actually happened and then I felt okay standing there.
Speaker 1: So, what I see is a well-dressed individual who appears to be asleep and they appear to have peed themselves a lot and it has run down their pants and run down the subway car.
Speaker 0: Did they have some sort of a diabetic attack?
Speaker 1: Ah, so I assume this at first and before I do anything, I just...
Speaker 0: Some sort of seizure of some kind?
Speaker 1: They seem to be sleeping peacefully like normally, but then I noticed something.
Speaker 0: They were just very drunken midday?
Speaker 1: Because then I noticed something.
Speaker 1: There was the individuals holding a napkin in their hands and their hand was sort of sitting near the crotch.
Speaker 1: and then I noticed that if you follow the trail of liquid, a diet coke can has rolled away.
Speaker 1: and it was very obvious that what actually happened is this guy fell asleep and spilled his coke on himself in the worst possible place and anyone who sees him thinks the worst.
Speaker 1: unless they notice the coke can and the rest of the situation around him.
Speaker 0: I mean, I imagine it would also smell like sugar and not like pee.
Speaker 1: You know, diet soda doesn't really smell like anything in my experience.
Speaker 0: I haven't made a habit of smelling it, but I know it doesn't smell like pee.
Speaker 1: I have because I had a friend in high school I will not name who shared something horrible.
Speaker 1: One of the reasons they drank diet soda as opposed to sugared soda was that, and I'm quoting this individual as exactly as I can remember from the year 1997, if you spill it, you don't have to clean it up because it doesn't get sticky like sugar.
Speaker 1: Yup, I'm just going to let that one hang out there.
Speaker 0: I guess if you want to just live in squalor and filth.
Speaker 1: There's a lot to unpack in that statement.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there's some news and we don't need to dwell on this one because I think it's obvious.
Speaker 1: So of course, he ignites formally and officially endorses Kamala Harris and Tim Walz for president of the United States.
Speaker 1: Like, obviously.
Speaker 0: I mean, I would endorse a potato or whichever one.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'd endorse a guy who was coming at me with a knife because at least he's only going to get me.
Speaker 1: And maybe a few other people.
Speaker 0: Barring some sort of revolution, constitutional changes, a flip flop of which party is which like what happened many, many decades ago.
Speaker 0: You know, somewhere in between Lincoln and FDR when there was a flip flop of which one was which.
Speaker 1: The party of Lincoln turned into the party of literally the opposite of Lincoln.
Speaker 0: If it was 1870, it's like, yeah, I'd be like, let's vote Republican, bro.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: I'm still mad that when I was in elementary and middle school, when you get to learning about the Civil War and Reconstruction, they always have the section on the radical Republicans and they tried to push too far.
Speaker 1: But if you actually read what the quote radical Republicans were doing back then, it was just perfectly reasonable, good stuff that would have been good for everybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, it doesn't really matter who it is, but I will make it a small note that this vice presidential candidate guy from Minnesota.
Speaker 1: Tim Walz, who a lot of people have never heard of, except weirdos who pay a lot of attention.
Speaker 0: I mean, I knew I had heard his name before.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that much about him.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, because he's famous for in a red state, barely winning office and then doing a whole bunch of really good stuff as fast and hard as possible.
Speaker 0: He's just a funny old guy.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I did know about him was that he is slightly less pro car than you would imagine from a Midwestern governor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He he signed legislation to basically give people money to buy e-bikes and things of that nature.
Speaker 0: And also he signed legislation to make, you know, what's known as complete streets.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Which is also good.
Speaker 0: So it's like he is a. you know, I'm sure he's not like like me saying bad cars, but he is less car than probably even the governor of New York.
Speaker 1: So but there is some some more stuff going on here because him being on the ticket, like now that it's kind of finalized and we know he's going to be running.
Speaker 1: Polls have turned around a little bit.
Speaker 1: And even though we all everyone else's geek nights knows that it shouldn't have mattered the names of the people on the ticket.
Speaker 1: All that matters is the policy of the power seeking coalition and the platform of policy for these two is not different from the platform that Joe Biden would have had.
Speaker 1: It's the same platform, same ideas, same stuff, same substance.
Speaker 1: But Americans are the way they are.
Speaker 1: And just the fact that it's different, younger people who are perceived differently and are talking in a different manner and are campaigning in a different way has actually materially shifted the race.
Speaker 1: Like polls are shifting pretty rapidly.
Speaker 0: Play to win.
Speaker 0: They should do more play to win, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, hooray, they did a little bit of play to win.
Speaker 0: And look what happens.
Speaker 0: Maybe they should play harder to win.
Speaker 1: And they seem to be playing harder to win.
Speaker 1: And that's just the thing I want to point out is my news that it's a low bar.
Speaker 0: It's a yeah, because the because the other team is has been all in on play to win for decades, my entire lives.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So but the tactic they're using that is like.
Speaker 1: I read a bunch of essays over the last week that are talking about how weirdly effective this is, is that he?
Speaker 1: they basically they're calling Trump and Vance weird and like they are weird.
Speaker 1: But no one seems to have realized that if you call it out openly like that, it's actually super effective.
Speaker 1: Because if you call someone out for being a fascist, their response is no.
Speaker 1: And they'll be like, they'll.
Speaker 1: you're being hysterical.
Speaker 1: But if you call someone weird, it's actually really hard for them to fight back against that, especially if they are weird, because whatever things they say to appear not weird are going to be weird.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're out there believing in conspiracy theories and all kinds of crazy nonsense.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: And the article I read that really put a fine point on this talked about how in countries outside of the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: people who have had to fight dictatorships have learned this very internally.
Speaker 1: And I think also I would hazard the Jewish people have internalized this to a great degree.
Speaker 1: One of the most powerful weapons against evil people is humor.
Speaker 1: Humor is a really powerful human weapon.
Speaker 1: And humor is working here.
Speaker 0: It's always.
Speaker 0: it's always because J.D.
Speaker 1: Vance apparently fucked a couch.
Speaker 1: And even though that's probably not true, that's what's making the news.
Speaker 1: And it's kind of working.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's something that else has always been true is that, you know, Trump is not a person who can tell a joke, nor does he laugh at a joke.
Speaker 0: No, he is.
Speaker 0: He is a humorless individual.
Speaker 0: You know, it's these these weirdos, fascists, whatever.
Speaker 0: The only thing that they find funny is harming other people, just like, you know, the bullies in your high school that vote for them.
Speaker 1: But the thing that freaks them out almost more than actually losing power is being laughed at and ridiculed like that.
Speaker 1: That like hits them right in whatever they have for us all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's the same as like I said, bullying high school.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, Nelson goes ahead.
Speaker 0: But as soon as he gets ahead, yeah.
Speaker 1: Are you making fun of the size of my automobile?
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, that aside, you got any news?
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: So I have this device, which is the Teenage Engineering EP 133.
Speaker 0: It is a noise making, sampling, composing device that Rym must never have.
Speaker 1: You know, I forgot.
Speaker 1: you had that until just now.
Speaker 1: You talked about it a while ago.
Speaker 1: And I didn't want to buy to get one.
Speaker 0: And I just didn't do not do that.
Speaker 0: And if you do, you must never touch it in my presence.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it is a it is a fun music audio making device that I do not regret purchasing.
Speaker 0: However, they have just announced a different but basically ninety nine percent same device.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I just clicked on the link for your news.
Speaker 1: I want this more.
Speaker 0: I wanted most things for the same price of three hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: They have released the EP 1320.
Speaker 0: And this one is basically the same fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Only it is themed in the medieval fashion.
Speaker 1: You got to attract his button and I'll poke his button.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: It basically does the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: It's the same exact device, the same buttons, the same everything.
Speaker 0: The LCD has been the graphics on it have been changed.
Speaker 0: And obviously these the colors and aesthetic of the device have been changed to now be medieval in fashion.
Speaker 0: Instead of being preloaded with very reasonable electronic music, drum samples, right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, synth samples and whatnot.
Speaker 0: It is loaded with, you know, sounds of hurdy gurdies and Gregorian chants.
Speaker 1: I note thundering drums.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You could get those samples and load them into this one.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's just the free samples that come with it.
Speaker 0: They're just wave files.
Speaker 0: So, you know, that's not.
Speaker 0: it's like they come with it, but they're not like exclusive to that.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could go and get them from somewhere.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the only other differences between the two, the only meaningful technological differences are the new one has one hundred and twenty eight megabytes of flash storage instead of sixty four.
Speaker 0: So double storage.
Speaker 0: But the all the medieval samples take up so much space that you only have thirty two megabytes of storage free for your own samples.
Speaker 0: Unless, of course, you delete some of the medieval ones, you know, and then make room.
Speaker 0: And the only other thing is that this one comes with a fundamental medieval styled arpeggiator that this was the old one does not have their otherwise identical same price.
Speaker 0: They just come with different samples.
Speaker 0: So that was an unexpected news only because you would think like if, you know, a this is a pretty recent device.
Speaker 0: You didn't think a successor or even an iteration or a version of it would come out so soon.
Speaker 0: It's like a big surprise.
Speaker 0: But also the specific direction they went is so far out of left field.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there was no way that you would imagine that.
Speaker 1: But the fact that not not only is it like out there, but it is so great, like it is crafted way more with way more care than you would expect for a gimmick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Like gimmicky.
Speaker 0: It makes me wonder.
Speaker 0: It's like that now that they've made a second edition of this device, it's like, are they going to keep going in this and like have a different versions with different themes and different sample packs?
Speaker 1: I mean, you can make one specifically and solely dedicated to late 70s to early 90s horror.
Speaker 1: And I bet that would go through real well.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, there are people selling music samples for decades, even on CDs or vinyl records and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: I feel like you could make some money if you just put together sample packs that were specifically already set up to go onto this device in a nice way with the correct numbering system.
Speaker 0: And then because it's like, you know, am I going to pay another three hundred dollars to get the same thing with more memory and, you know, a different aesthetic?
Speaker 0: It's like, no, there's no.
Speaker 0: why would I do that?
Speaker 0: It's pointless.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But if they said, hey, five bucks for the medieval sample pack, I bet I share.
Speaker 1: this thing just looks so good.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it is a. it is a fun device that has, you know, it does not have the capabilities of, you know, some other competing devices.
Speaker 0: I forget the exact like the Roland sampler machine thingy.
Speaker 0: that's way more powerful.
Speaker 0: The main feature that this thing lacks is resampling ability.
Speaker 0: So what can happen is like, you know, normally it's like, OK, you take a sample, you would play some you know, you'd sequence like, you know, some some beats.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then you would take that, you know, that beat that you've sequenced and sample it to make a new wave file that you can now play with a single press.
Speaker 0: And now that would now sort of expand what you can do.
Speaker 0: You could now sequence the whole thing that you just sequenced.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And also save in terms of the resources available to you, you know, to make new sequences, you've now sort of reduced that because you've taken a whole bunch of stuff that you put together and now just turned it into a new sample.
Speaker 0: This can't do that.
Speaker 0: And other more professional ones, that's like a base feature.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, for three hundred bucks, it does a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you want to deal with your pulses and your metrim, your ignito.
Speaker 0: So how about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: One last little news, partly just because it's the kind of thing that you never really thought actually happens in the real world.
Speaker 1: So if you didn't notice recently, the U.S.
Speaker 1: President, Joe Biden, negotiated with the Russian Empire a prisoner exchange where basically they do that.
Speaker 0: They do this every once in a while.
Speaker 0: The last time was for the basketball player.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this one was a much bigger one and it was kind of historic for a number of reasons.
Speaker 1: But basically we got back a bunch of hostages and we gave them like literal assassins that we had captured.
Speaker 1: And you know what, though?
Speaker 0: Good job capturing the assassins.
Speaker 0: Whoever is the assassin capture.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: It's like the fact that we even captured an assassin at any point, it's like, damn, that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, because you think about it, it's like, what did they do?
Speaker 0: They just took some normal people hostage, like journalists.
Speaker 0: It's like that's not very high skill.
Speaker 0: That doesn't seem difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if I go go 13 locked up in my closet and then I send him to jail and he writes, that tells me that our our people are much more skilled at capturing than they are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, how come they haven't kept?
Speaker 0: I mean, it could be that they haven't captured American assassins because we don't have assassins.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Not evil assassinators.
Speaker 1: I mean, we used to be.
Speaker 1: We definitely used to be.
Speaker 0: Or if we are right now, we're really good at making sure no one knows it.
Speaker 0: But, you know, they're assassinating and they're not good at it.
Speaker 1: But so the story, basically two of the well, two of the prisoners who were swapped back to Russia were deep agents living in Europe.
Speaker 1: They were living in Slovenia, posing as an Argentine couple, but they were actually Russian spies.
Speaker 0: But they were like, they were for real Russian spies.
Speaker 0: They were like, these are people that are like, yeah, Putin's awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm going to spy for him and yell them out.
Speaker 1: Unregistered like because, you know, there are spies who register with countries and that's like kind of accepted.
Speaker 1: Like the U.S.
Speaker 1: will say, hey, this guy's coming to the country.
Speaker 1: He's going to live here.
Speaker 1: He is a spy.
Speaker 1: And Russia will be like, OK, thank you for telling us.
Speaker 1: This is our spy.
Speaker 1: And of course, there's more spies we don't tell each other about.
Speaker 1: But so these two were for real spies.
Speaker 1: They got captured.
Speaker 1: They had children and they were living in such a deep cover that their children did not know that their parents were Russian agents and are and were now sent to Russia, where they have never been and do not speak Russian.
Speaker 1: And they are Russian citizens and they can't really ever leave Russia again, at least not for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: And according to reporting from multiple news agencies, including CNN, they learned of this as they were being driven to the airport to be sent back to Russia.
Speaker 0: No, I can't wait to read those kids' biographies.
Speaker 1: There is no universe for these kids.
Speaker 1: Don't tell their story at some point.
Speaker 0: If there if this was a best selling novel for the drugstore, one of those kids would assassinate you.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this I saw a picture of this plane.
Speaker 1: I'm making this my thing of the day, because, you know, one of the things I'm kind of weird about is I like.
Speaker 1: I like to learn a lot about fighter jets and bombers and aircraft and military aircraft, that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It's the thing I'd like to know a lot about.
Speaker 1: And I didn't actually know.
Speaker 1: I'd heard of the XB-70 Valkyrie, but I didn't like know what plane it was.
Speaker 1: It's just like I knew it was a bomber.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know about like.
Speaker 0: all I know is that there's a bunch of planes that the US, you know, mostly NASA makes that all and any plane that says X at the start.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's some kind of test plane that they made.
Speaker 0: one of that some crazy genius, you know, heroic daredevil test pilot flew for NASA one time.
Speaker 0: And they never made a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: And a lot of those things are like the one model rocket I made as a kid.
Speaker 1: that was just a D engine with fins and a nose cone strapped to it.
Speaker 0: Maybe it didn't even have a pilot.
Speaker 0: And it was.
Speaker 0: it was, you know, it's like, you know, any.
Speaker 0: it's like, I guess, and the data has just continuously done this of like make planes in this X series that are like crazy test plane ideas that maybe someone will fly.
Speaker 0: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: And they learn from that.
Speaker 0: And maybe that technology gets into planes that are mass produced and maybe it doesn't.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So this one did not get mass produced.
Speaker 0: But none of the X's do.
Speaker 0: But it's just maybe technology from them would.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no technology from this one got mass produced either.
Speaker 1: But that's that's the thing.
Speaker 1: That's why it's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Independently yesterday, I saw a picture of a plane that looked fake.
Speaker 1: And the caption was like, this is the XP 70 Valkyrie.
Speaker 1: What a like crazy plane.
Speaker 1: And I was like, that that can't be real.
Speaker 1: And I did.
Speaker 1: this video is yes, it was real.
Speaker 1: It looks weird.
Speaker 1: It was weird.
Speaker 1: It was a terrible idea.
Speaker 1: And there's a reason we never turned that into a thing.
Speaker 0: The X planes are a series of experimental U.S.
Speaker 0: aircraft and rockets used to test and evaluate new technologies and aerodynamic concepts.
Speaker 1: So this thing is like this weird looking crazy plane that was designed to fly supersonic like a Concorde.
Speaker 1: And it was a bomber.
Speaker 1: And it's the idea was it'll fly so fast that nothing could shoot it down and it just drops its bomb along the way.
Speaker 1: And it was massive with a weird shape.
Speaker 1: And it flew.
Speaker 1: Basically, they caused sonic booms, which were a problem.
Speaker 1: But the sonic booms were what we're making it fly.
Speaker 1: Like it's I don't know much.
Speaker 1: That's not a thing I know much about.
Speaker 1: So this video explains what the hell the deal was with this plane.
Speaker 1: And you can even see footage of the prototype flying because it doesn't look like it could actually fly if you see what this thing looks like.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: On Wikipedia, there is the list of X planes.
Speaker 0: And they're literally.
Speaker 0: most of them are number just one, two, three, four.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And just at a glance, the notable ones are the X 13 VertiJet, which, yes, takes off vertically like a rocket.
Speaker 0: There is the X 22, which has.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Look at those tilt rotors.
Speaker 0: And I guess the other one that really catches your eye is the X for seven a Pegasus, which is a triangle.
Speaker 0: This one's like, oh, the highest number.
Speaker 0: Oh, the X sixty five crane looks like something the evil guy in the James Bond movie is going to use.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's not.
Speaker 0: that's actually the year on.
Speaker 0: that is twenty twenty five.
Speaker 0: So that might be next year.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: This thing also, if you look at it, the back of it looks extra fake because it almost looks like a Star Wars thing because it's got six engines all crammed together, like in the middle.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have this thing?
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, there's an old pun.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you've heard this pun before.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Why do fish always sing off key?
Speaker 0: Because you can't tune a fish.
Speaker 0: How do you tune a fish?
Speaker 0: Adjust their scale.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: What's the difference between a piano, a fish and some glue?
Speaker 0: You can tune a piano, but you can't tune a fish.
Speaker 0: What about the glue?
Speaker 0: I knew you'd get stuck on that.
Speaker 0: OK, so it's an old pun, but somebody took that old pun and they said, wait a minute, I can tune a fish.
Speaker 0: And sure enough, they sort of arguably did or did not tune a fish.
Speaker 0: What they did in this YouTube video is they basically sent electricity through a fish from one end to the other because, you know, it's flesh.
Speaker 0: It can conduct electricity.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I like how it has a warning around like the dangers of this and the voltages pretty early on.
Speaker 0: And so, you know, if you sample the fish, you know, if you put electricity near the head end and you get it coming out, ground the tail end, it'll go through one side and come out the other.
Speaker 0: And if you were to sample the electricity and sort of close the circuit at different points along the fish's body, you're going to have a different voltage.
Speaker 0: And so as long as you get your probes in the right positions on the fish, you can then effectively have each probe be, you know, tuned to a specific frequency to produce a specific sound.
Speaker 0: And then you can sort of play the fish, arguably.
Speaker 0: Of course, it will go out of tune as the fish dries out or decays, the temperature changes or, you know, it's like I like the section of problems.
Speaker 1: One, hard to play.
Speaker 1: Two, screeches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can basically just, you know, no reason you can't MIDI control this fish and just take the voltage out into some kind of amplifier or whatever and hear noise.
Speaker 1: Now to complete the circuit, you play this and then you send that output to an AM antenna and then you touch the AM antenna with a hot dog and that's your speaker.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it was just funny that someone went that far with the pun that they did the, I guess, the closest that can realistically be said to tuning a fish.
Speaker 0: I guess the only other way to tune a fish would be to get a fish that is capable of making sound, right?
Speaker 0: Obviously it would be unethical because most of those are like dolphins and whales.
Speaker 1: Unless you trained a dolphin consensually to sing in certain keys, you could make that happen.
Speaker 0: The problem is that it's a melon.
Speaker 1: A dolphin's not a fish.
Speaker 0: It's not a fish.
Speaker 0: So you need to get a fish that can make sound with its body and then somehow tune it to produce notes that are on, you know, key.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Alright, so way back in the year 2013, we did a show that was adjacent to this.
Speaker 1: The show was titled Farts.
Speaker 1: So today we were talking about fragrances.
Speaker 1: So the other side of that F spectrum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I mean, you know, basically fragrances are a thing that I never thought about at all in my life other than when I would walk through a department store and I had to go through the smelly section on my way to the section of something I was actually going to buy.
Speaker 1: In middle school, I sometimes just like to burn the incense in my room.
Speaker 1: There's a thing I would do like.
Speaker 1: it was a nice smell.
Speaker 1: And also, I wore a little bit of cologne pretty much every day for most of my life until I left college.
Speaker 1: And now I don't use cologne, but I do wear fragrances on a daily basis still.
Speaker 0: You know, there are some things you have that have a fragrance like the deodorant I use has some kind of fragrance, I guess.
Speaker 1: I used to though.
Speaker 1: I actually never liked deodorant that smelled like anything.
Speaker 1: And for most of my life, I used an old Arm & Hammer deodorant that had no smell.
Speaker 1: It smelled like nothing.
Speaker 1: It was just antibacterial.
Speaker 1: And it was great.
Speaker 0: I mean, the one I have is also just antibacterial.
Speaker 1: But they discontinued it and I never found one that was quite nice enough to replace it.
Speaker 0: I have heard about this other deodorant that I don't know if it's actually good, but I have heard things about that are positive.
Speaker 0: It is called...
Speaker 1: Because I'm pretty married to the Bear Glove.
Speaker 1: I've only worn four deodorants intentionally other than like emergencies in my life.
Speaker 1: Because once I find one I like, I wear it forever.
Speaker 1: And three times in my life, a deodorant I liked was discontinued by the company that made it.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the deodorant that I heard of because it was written about on Wirecutter is Lavalin.
Speaker 0: L-A-V-I-L-I-N.
Speaker 0: It is a gender neutral deodorant.
Speaker 0: It does not have aluminum, alcohol, or, you know, bad stuff in it.
Speaker 0: And supposedly, according to them, it will keep you deodorized for like 72 hours.
Speaker 0: Even if you take a shower or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't feel like any... I'm fine with putting a little deodorant on every morning after I shower.
Speaker 1: That feels like it's good enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is, you know, it's a zinc oxide base.
Speaker 0: Basically it's zinc oxide that kills all the bacteria.
Speaker 0: That's how this one works.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But, you know, fragrances, I didn't think about them until, see previous Geek Nights episode, a box of moderately expensive, you know, perfumes and colognes just showed up on our doorstep.
Speaker 0: that was meant for a Canadian drugstore in Edmonton.
Speaker 0: And then I had to sell them all because I tried to give them back and I was unable to.
Speaker 0: and then we just sold them and made a few hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: Mostly gave them away to people we knew.
Speaker 0: They were worth like, you know, a hundred bucks each, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, hey.
Speaker 0: But since then, it's like, oh, you know, now that, you know, we've had that experience, it's like, oh, fragrances are now a thing that like have now entered my consciousness, right?
Speaker 0: Because I'm not buying any, but it was a thing I never thought about, but now because I got some for free and had to sell them, I now thought about them.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I'll say I do appreciate and enjoy a subtle good fragrance on a person like it's just.
Speaker 1: I've always liked it.
Speaker 1: Like I always like to wear a little bit of cologne, but at the same time, I have definitely a lot of people seem to not understand the concept of moderation and subtle when it comes to fragrances.
Speaker 1: Nothing is worse.
Speaker 1: Well, few things are worse than being near someone who is a fan of Axe Body Spray.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are people who, you know, are into perfumes or fragrances and they pour colognes and they put on too much and it is overpowering to be near the person, even if they get a one that smells really fucking good.
Speaker 0: Too much of it is overpowering.
Speaker 0: You know, noses are sensitive, at least if people have a sense of smell.
Speaker 1: Well, because it's supposed to be subtle.
Speaker 1: It's supposed to be like a little accent when you're around.
Speaker 0: And it's supposed to mostly be stronger when someone's like really close to you.
Speaker 0: Not just, you know, it's like if someone's just standing near you, it's supposed to smell like a little bit.
Speaker 0: And if they get close to you, then they're supposed to be able to smell it like, ooh.
Speaker 1: I will uncharitably say that I've encountered three people, three kinds of people in my life who way overdue the scents.
Speaker 1: Kind number one, just can't smell and don't realize they smell that much, which I think increased after covid.
Speaker 1: I noticed I feel like I've encountered people in my daily life way more often who are wearing way too much perfume.
Speaker 1: And I feel like it might be related in some way.
Speaker 1: The second kind, people who don't bathe enough and are trying to cover it up.
Speaker 1: And that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: like just if you're to be clear, that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: That is not a successful and effective strategy.
Speaker 0: But it is.
Speaker 0: There is one case where that's an acceptable strategy, which is where you were in a tough spot, right?
Speaker 0: If you're like a person who just generally doesn't bathe enough and you're covering it up with fragrances on the regular, fucking take a shower.
Speaker 0: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: But if you were, say, you know, out in the woods and you got stanky or something or who knows what happened.
Speaker 0: But then you have to, you know, on short notice without the ability to bathe or shower, have to appear in public or in a social situation.
Speaker 0: Maybe you can successfully, you know, avoid a problem by, you know, but that's that's the exception.
Speaker 1: That's more like a reasonable use case.
Speaker 1: But, you know, a lot of geek nights, listeners go to conventions.
Speaker 1: We know that happens.
Speaker 1: And then the third kind are I'm just going to say people who are weird and I don't get it like they seem to do it on purpose and get mad if anyone complains.
Speaker 1: I've definitely had co-workers in the past who were like that and I just avoided them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, the other thing you got to realize is that even if you pick something that smells good, it's not going to smell good to everyone.
Speaker 0: And it's something you're inflicting on everyone, you know, within a certain radius of you, depending on how strongly you apply it.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, I think in certain situations it's really not acceptable to use anything, you know, fragrancy that is, you know, over a certain very low strength level, even if it's like a smell that like the majority of people would say is is like excellent and they just want to fucking smell it all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean like.
Speaker 1: imagine if you knew someone who just smelled overpoweringly of fresh baked cookies.
Speaker 1: Like you're standing in a bakery with ten ovens all going making shortbread cookies.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like that's great if you walk past them on the street briefly, but if they're sitting next to you for like a whole concert or something, right?
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 1: So from middle school until about, I would say the year 2003, the cologne I wore every single day was a little dab of Stetson.
Speaker 1: I always put a little bit of Stetson.
Speaker 1: That was just, that was the scent I liked.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I mean, what else would you know about when you're that young?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I knew of colognes and I remember going with my parents to the store and we tried a bunch and I was like Stetson, that's the one I like.
Speaker 1: And I remember that my parents both thought, well, that's unfortunate.
Speaker 1: He picked the bad one, but whatever.
Speaker 1: That's it is Stetson has a reputation among people who care about fragrances as being extremely 13 year old boys like Stetson and nobody else does.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's interesting that actually quite recently, uh, teenagers, you know, boys have been, you know, gaining interest in colognes and fragrances.
Speaker 1: Which I'm glad for because that's breaking down another arbitrarily gendered thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I saw like an article about that.
Speaker 0: Like, Hey, the kids these days, they're into the fragrances.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, they're using their allowance on the, you know, something in this, you know, this teenage boys on TikTok, you know, collecting colognes and shit.
Speaker 0: And then sure enough, I was in a cosmetic store, right?
Speaker 0: You know, with someone else just waiting around and teenage boys were in the smelly section, smelling everything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, and I was like, Oh, I guess the article was not lying.
Speaker 0: There's there they are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Um, I never seen that before in my whole life.
Speaker 0: I don't think that article is what made him do it.
Speaker 0: So it's, it's gaining in popularity.
Speaker 0: There's also, I've learned, uh, sort of, you know, there are the popular mega brands and fashion designers and labels that sell expensive ones and fancy bottles, right?
Speaker 0: You get them at the store and, you know, those have merit.
Speaker 0: They're not like all evil or anything, but there's a whole bunch of people out there who are like mega fragrance nerds.
Speaker 0: And we're not just talking like, obviously there's a whole world of indie fragrances, small companies making custom, you know, small batshit, high prices, low prices.
Speaker 0: There's companies out there who make, they try to imitate the expensive fragrance, right?
Speaker 0: And they obviously can't say, Hey, this is the, this is a copy of the, of the fragrance.
Speaker 0: that's $500 an ounce for 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: They can't mention it, but they do everything they can to wink, wink, like, yo dog, this smells the same as that expensive thing.
Speaker 0: Only it's way cheaper.
Speaker 1: As far as I understand sense can't be copyrighted.
Speaker 0: No, it's just your, you can just get your label, your trademark and et cetera.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the, you just put the same, you know, you try to match the smell in a different bottle.
Speaker 0: Um, you're good to go.
Speaker 0: But then there's nerds out there making their own fragrances.
Speaker 0: I actually saw like, Hey, you can pay to take a class.
Speaker 0: And in the class they show you like making, you know, it's like, Hey, make a cologne or a perfume.
Speaker 1: And if you take this class, that sounds fun because it's not intuitive.
Speaker 1: Like the, like the ratios of things and what chemicals you need, not what you'd expect if you don't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you can like take, you know, you could, I guess you could then buy component chemicals.
Speaker 0: Obviously it would be expensive if you wanted to use the precious ambergris, but you could get, you know, just use cheaper things, flowers, dried flower, who knows what you're throwing in there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, anything that smells really can be used.
Speaker 0: It's like, you think like, Oh, I'll make a, you know, vanilla fragrance.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, you don't just take fucking vanilla extract to rub it on yourself.
Speaker 0: Cause that ain't gonna work.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You had to, it's not, you know, that's the sec could give you the smell you need, you know, some vanilla beans, but you're going to need some extra stuff to like get it to stick to your body.
Speaker 0: To emit the smell enough so that you can smell it, but to emit it slowly so that it lasts a long time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then the other thing I've, I've heard a lot about is that, you know, even though, you know, in the bottle, you know, a lot of people, you spray it on a paper and you smell it right.
Speaker 0: Different people.
Speaker 0: Obviously have different sweat, right?
Speaker 0: Different skins, different, you know, chemistry going on.
Speaker 0: So when you spray it on yourself or a different person, the chemistry may or may not like mess with the perfume.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or, or fragrance in some way.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't smell, even though it smells great to you when you just spray it in the air, whatever you spray it on yourself, it might suddenly alter it in some way.
Speaker 0: Uh, you know, even if you're clean showered.
Speaker 1: Or it might mix with, like a lot of people don't think about this, different fabrics actually have their own sense and will absorb sense in different ways.
Speaker 1: Like, uh, many of you out there, if you're not like familiar with this, think about the smell of that cheap black suit that you only wear when like you have to go to a special occasion.
Speaker 1: Otherwise it's in your closet.
Speaker 1: That smell will interact with your perfumes.
Speaker 1: And a big part of why a lot of people wear cologne and cologne is the way it is, is basically because it'll kind of mask that slightly.
Speaker 1: Smell of the suit that you only wear a few times a year, the cheap one.
Speaker 1: But, uh, I also like, not that I'm an expert, like I only thought about smells I like and smells I don't like, but I always made a distinction between an everyday cologne and the cologne I would wear when I went out to like a special thing.
Speaker 1: And even now I still have a bottle of my regular Stetson versus the country Stetson that smelled more like formal cologne, but I couldn't for the life of me explain the difference between them.
Speaker 1: But I, I just distinctly have this categorization of that smells like a formal cologne versus that smells like an everyday cologne.
Speaker 1: Can't say where that came from.
Speaker 1: That might just be me, but it might just be partly that I associate with formal events, the sense of the kinds of colognes that adults and people would wear at formal events when I was young and it just imprinted on me.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, even if you don't know anything about fragrances, right?
Speaker 0: As little as I know, it's like this obviously like, hey, you know, you get a fragrance that smells like, I don't know, a fruit.
Speaker 0: I love, I love to smell fruits.
Speaker 1: Well, like the burglar that I wear that basically just smells like apples.
Speaker 1: Like that's what that smell is.
Speaker 0: But you wouldn't, you know, you wouldn't want to smell like, you know, Apple is not really an appropriate smell for like, you know, a formal ball or something.
Speaker 1: You know, you want to roll into the opera smelling like bubble gum.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But you know, a bubble gum fragrance might be really awesome on certain occasions.
Speaker 0: There's also, you know, if you think about in your life, even if you're someone who is not interested in fragrances in general and having a particular smell, right, you just don't want to be stinky.
Speaker 0: If you think about it, it's like if you have a sense of smell, I bet there are smells that you enjoy smelling whoever you are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And if I think about it, it's like, hey, could I get a fragrance that smells like fucking magic cards or any S cartridge that's new out of the box or old library book?
Speaker 0: or it's like smells that you like, you know, and it's sure enough.
Speaker 0: Yes, there are.
Speaker 0: There are not all of those that I've mentioned.
Speaker 0: I looked for some of those and was unable to find them, but there do exist.
Speaker 0: I saw one that was like ink, ink smell.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot out there for people who enjoy.
Speaker 0: And so that's the second.
Speaker 0: use of the fragrance is not just to, you know, the social aspect of covering up a bad smell or smelling good for others, but just there are people who get fragrances and use them because they want to smell the smell.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They'll spray it on like their pillow and go to sleep and smell a good smell.
Speaker 1: I have an adorable story from like high school.
Speaker 1: So I dated a girl in high school and when I went off to college, we'd already broken up by that point.
Speaker 1: Like it was a high school relationship, but she asked for a bottle of the cologne I wore so she could spray it on a stuffed animal that I gave her once to remember me.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, you can go to the store and buy some.
Speaker 1: That's a cute high school thing, but smells are intensely tied to human memory.
Speaker 1: Very.
Speaker 1: To a degree that we are not going to explain because we're not experts in this, go read Wikipedia, but it's real.
Speaker 1: Like this is a profound thing.
Speaker 0: So for some reason, the sense of smell is more tied to memory than other senses.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If I see something I've seen before, you know, I might remember it.
Speaker 0: If I hear something I've heard before, I remember it.
Speaker 0: But if I smell something I've smelled before, my brain will like go back and find like the moment that I smelled that same smell.
Speaker 1: So broadly, how that works is kind of fascinating.
Speaker 1: I'll get the shortest summary because this is something I've read a lot about over the last couple of years.
Speaker 1: Basically, your brain is sort of ticking periodically and like linking a bunch of neurons to form memories.
Speaker 1: And it has this like clock rate almost to forming memories.
Speaker 1: And each memory is linked to sets of sensations that are happening at the same time.
Speaker 1: But sense are like they're all arbitrary.
Speaker 1: They're all treated kind of the same.
Speaker 1: But because sense are rarer to be strong and due to a bunch of other factors, you'll tend to remember things where you smell.
Speaker 1: Memories where you smelled the same thing at that time will be connected to each other, even if the only thing connecting them is the smell.
Speaker 1: And that's part of it because our brain just takes this cadence of here's 10 bits, here's 10 bits, here's 10 bits.
Speaker 1: And then it just makes like this lateral database across those bits.
Speaker 0: The point is, if you can get a bottle of liquid that smells very close to or exactly the way something smelled when you had a positive time memory in your life and you want to evoke that memory again, that is a useful thing to have around.
Speaker 1: I just imagine the smell of magic cards and vivid memories of specific times.
Speaker 1: I played magic in middle school.
Speaker 1: It came flooding back into my brain just now.
Speaker 1: Just by imagining the smell of a magic card.
Speaker 1: But I've seen, I was reading a cool Reddit thread of people who are trying to hack their brains to improve their memory or to otherwise get better at certain video games by using sense to encode and help them remember specific kinds of things.
Speaker 0: You probably could do that to some extent.
Speaker 1: You probably could do that.
Speaker 1: Think about the old string around the finger.
Speaker 1: that was the thing before smartphones existed.
Speaker 0: So one thing I do worry about with fragrances is that the fragrance industry has had a history of animal testings.
Speaker 1: A lot of it's gone away from that recently.
Speaker 0: A lot of it has gone away from that, but it's like at the same time, we need some amount of testing because it's like, hey, you don't get ingredients when you buy.
Speaker 0: Usually they'll tell you what it smells like.
Speaker 0: Ah yes, base notes of this and accents of that.
Speaker 1: I actually avoid things that don't publish their ingredient list somewhere.
Speaker 1: That's quite a reason I wear badger now is my primary sense because they publish full ingredient lists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but some things it's like, hey, you buy this fragrance.
Speaker 0: It's like, is that harmful to you?
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised.
Speaker 1: I really like the smell of mercury and cadmium.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen either way.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen information that says, ah yes, this fragrance gave people cancer, but I haven't seen the opposite either.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you have to imagine that like some mystery chemical, like smelling it all day, every day, it's like, or, you know, or frequently if you're wearing it, you know, a lot is like, is that, you know, damaging lungs?
Speaker 0: Maybe not.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's perfectly safe, right?
Speaker 0: It's just like smelling flowers is not going to hurt you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: It doesn't seem, you know, it's sort of an unnecessary thing.
Speaker 0: Who knows what the hell's in there.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, it's like, were they, you know, all the tests are that were those like long term tests.
Speaker 0: I don't think they were that long term.
Speaker 1: So usually, so there are a lot of sense we'll get a USDA rating that they've been inspected.
Speaker 1: There's also the concept of there's a term in the food industry, but also in the cosmetics industry generally recognized as safe.
Speaker 1: Which is a good indication that there's no evidence that that thing is specifically harmful in quantities you would encounter.
Speaker 0: It does only use for you.
Speaker 0: We don't tell you what's in there.
Speaker 0: But the things that we've used are basically things everyone knows.
Speaker 0: There's nothing weird or outlandish.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's also a really good label you can look for.
Speaker 1: It looks like a little rabbit sort of jumping and it'll say like cruelty free under it.
Speaker 1: That specifically means not tested on animals.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah.
Speaker 0: Other than that, it's like, okay, you know, it's sort of like this, uh, you know, I guess that's a cool hobby.
Speaker 0: if you're into it and you know, it's, it's something useful for a special occasion, but it's also something you can safely ignore and save all your money.
Speaker 0: As long as you don't smell bad, you can smell like nothing with deodorant only and ignore the world of fragrance as I did until a box of it showed up on my porch.
Speaker 1: I would advise don't put fragrances in your laundry.
Speaker 1: That just sucks.
Speaker 1: That sucks.
Speaker 1: That smells bad.
Speaker 1: Uh, also full body deodorant is a scam kids.
Speaker 1: Like that's not a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In terms of like, you know, if you want a fragrance, right, you should buy a fragrance on its own, right?
Speaker 0: You should, if there are other things you are buying, contain fragrance.
Speaker 0: That's, you generally would like to avoid that, you know, especially things like, you know, a skincare product or a shampoo or because, you know, those can often, you know, lead to allergic reactions or other irritations or who knows what, I guess, you know, the hand soap by your sink.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: It's maybe okay for that to have a fragrance in it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That could be nice.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: A little like lavender usually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, the cleaning spray.
Speaker 0: Maybe you can get a lemon cleaning spray, but it's not really necessary.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of times that smells like lemon because it's got lemon.
Speaker 1: It's got acid in it.
Speaker 1: It's got like concentrated lemon juice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: But like your laundry detergent, your dishwasher detergent.
Speaker 1: I want, I want all those things to smell like nothing.
Speaker 1: Those things smell like that's right.
Speaker 0: All those things you should get ones that don't smell.
Speaker 1: My daily wear lately, I tend to, I use the badger stuff, so I'm all about like bergamot, vanilla bean, black pepper, like those kinds of smells.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's one more, one more fragrance related pro tip that I have learned, right?
Speaker 0: Is that sometimes there is a bad smell in an area, right?
Speaker 0: That you must enter the area with the bad smell.
Speaker 0: Most often the porta potty.
Speaker 0: Um, now there is a product, but I'm sure you could just get any old fragrance to achieve the same effect, but there is a product called Poo-Pourri.
Speaker 1: We're not usually.
Speaker 0: most of the time people think about this product or similar products and they imagine themselves pooping and making a stinky bathroom and then politely spraying so that the next entrance to the bathroom does not have to experience.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The, the odor that is, that is, that is perfectly legitimate, but people don't often think of this strategy that I only learned within the past year or two of you are about to enter a porta potty most likely or otherwise disgusting public bathroom and there is a smell, but you really got to go and you don't have another choice.
Speaker 0: You can actually Poo-Pourri in there, right?
Speaker 0: Close the door.
Speaker 0: Wait a second.
Speaker 0: You have now vanquished most or all of the odor.
Speaker 0: Go in and do your business.
Speaker 0: And if you're extra polite, spray on the way out too.
Speaker 0: And there you go.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Uh, so if you are, you know, if you got like a bag of stuff you carry with you all the time, or if you happen to be going somewhere like an outdoor music festival, that might be something you want to make sure is on the packing list.
Speaker 1: The listener just posted the noblest of acts.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowclue.com for show notes, discussion, links, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Linky, Jim Jurek, Lily Tenderplay, Kace Kerr, Mix Music, Krista Dodd, Christopher Orr, Clinton Walton, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erikson, Shervin Von Hurl, and a whole bunch of people who are giving us like a dollar or a pound or I say a euro sign there.
Speaker 1: Uh, so yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, Tim Wallace is cool, J.D.
Speaker 1: Vance is weird, and tonight I leave you with... And I got to tell you, his running mate shares his dangerous and backward agenda for this country.
Speaker 1: J.D.
Speaker 1: Vance literally, literally wrote the foreword for the architect of the Project 2025 agenda.
Speaker 1: Like all regular people I grew up with in the heartland, J.D.
Speaker 1: studied at Yale, had his career funded by Silicon Valley billionaires, and then wrote a bestseller trashing that community.
Speaker 1: Come on!
Speaker 1: That's not what Middle America is.
Speaker 1: And I got to tell you, I can't wait to debate the guy.
Speaker 1: That is if he's willing to get off the couch and show up.
Speaker 1: I got to tell you, pointing out, just an observation of mine that I made.
Speaker 1: I just have to say it.
Speaker 1: You know it, you feel it.
Speaker 1: These guys are creepy, and yes, just weird as hell.
Speaker 1: That's what you see.
Speaker 0: That's what you see.